A Guide to the Tazewell family papers, 1623-1930
Library of Virginia
- 26 May 1830 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Beverley Tucker in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-political and personal matters
- 9 October 1841 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Francis H. Smith to John N. Tazewell-VMI and the general education system of the state
- 5 August 1842 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Francis H. Smith to John N. Tazewell-early financial conditions of VMI-includes a statement of receipts and disbursements from its start until July 1842
- 15 July 1843 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Francis H. Smith to John N. Tazewell-financial conditions at VMI-postscript by Captain Thomas H. Williamson
- 5 August 1843 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Francis H. Smith to John N. Tazewell-appointment of cadets to scholarships
- 19 March 1846 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Francis H. Smith to John N. Tazewell-original library of VMI
- 6 April 1848 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Francis H. Smith to John N. Tazewell-society of alumni-copy of resolutions of the board of visitors of VMI
- 9 November 1832 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-their boarding house-South Carolina and nullification-Philip Pendleton Barbour's letter
- 18 December 1832 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-politics-tariff-nullification crisis-Jackson's proclamation-results in Virginia-Ritchie-political news
- 16 January 1833 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-public deposits-other political news-Tazewell elected governor
- April 1833 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Tazewell's letters on the Proclamation (published as by "A Virginian")-if in pamphlet form, asks for copy-nullification and Henry Clay-the crisis and Clay's bill which might solve it-effect on Virginia politics
- 20 October 1833 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-politics-Leigh and election-BUS, treasury and the president
- 24 November 1833 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-removal of deposits-removal of executive officers by the president-politics-Secretary of Treasury position and Jackson
- 1 June 1834 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-their correspondence-Patton and remarks he allegedly made-did not-Patton and Virginia--politics
- 29 October 1834 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-current congressional session--politics
- 18 December 1834 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-deposit bill-U.S. and France-the upcoming presidential contest-Virginia and politics
- 16 January 1836 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-antislavery petition going through mails-whether such things can be sent through the mails-relations with France-abolition petitions-presidential politics
- 4 May 1836 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Tazewell's retirement-presidential race
- 12 June 1836 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-politics-comments on government-Congress meeting
- 21 November 1837 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-his visit to Norfolk-politics-financial situation of country--Calhoun
- 18 February 1837 [1838] (Box 12, Folder 8)
  18 February 1837 [1838]-John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Tazewell's enquiries to the Secretary of the Treasury-subtreasury and specie
- 17 February 1847 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-figs
- 20 May 1853 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Taliaferro v. Wilkinson and Ambler v. Wilkinson
- 6 January 1858 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  John M. Patton in Washington to Littleton Waller Tazewell-Ambler v. Wilkinson
- 26 January 1858 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- 29 January 1858 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- 7 April 1759 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  deposition of Mary Hall in Skinker vs. Newton-King George County
- 7 April 1759 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  deposition of Stephen McCormick in Skinker vs. Newton-King George County
- 7 April 1759 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  deposition of Willoughby Newton in Skinker vs. Newton-King George County
- 23 April 1790 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  deed for Town Point stock between Robert Freeman of Warren County NC and John Nivison of Portsmouth VA-recorded in Norfolk-25 October 1790, 28 February 1791, and 1 March 1791
- (Box 12, Folder 10)
  before 1628-John Blow 100 acres-land later deserted and granted to Peter Walker
- (Box 12, Folder 10)
  copies of 17th century land patents on the Eastern Shore made by Littleton Waller Tazewell in 1835-land in original patents probably became part of Tazewell's own holdings in Northampton County
- 1623 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  John Blow 140 acres-with sundry leases-deserted and granted to Peter Walker 25 September 1645
- 3 February 1626 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  William Epes 450 acres-50 acres sold to Elias Taylor whose admx sold it to John Rosyer-400 acres and residence deserted and granted to Anthony Hoskins
- 14 March 1628 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  William Andrews 100 acres-sold to Elias Taylor whose admx sold it to John Rosyer
- 18 June 1632 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Roger Saunders 300 acres-with a lease
- 25 June 1635 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  William Andrews 100 acres
- 18 June 1636 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Lewin Denwood 150 acres
- 24 June 1636 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  William Bibby 400 acres
- 22 December 1636 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Francis Stockley 50 acres-passed to Obedience Johnson son and heir of Lt. Col. Thomas Johnson-sold by Johnson to Robert Hutchison-sold by Hutchison to Major William Andrews
- 29 October 1637 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Henry Willsonn 50 acres-passed to Obedience Johnson son and heir of Lt. Col. Thomas Johnson-sold by Johnson to Robert Hutchison-sold by Hutchison to Major William Andrews
- 1 November 1637 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  George Traveller 500 acres-with a lease
- 19 April 1638 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Francis Martin 50 acres-deserted and granted to John Rosyer
- 1645 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Peter Walker 150 acres-sold by Walker to Thomas Seatherbury 7 May 1652-sold by Seatherbury to Major William Andrews 26 November 1662
- 27 July 1645 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  James Jackson 100 acres
- 10 July 1646 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  John Rosyer 200 acres
- 20 March 1647 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  William Many 150 acres
- 24 July 1651 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  George Truehett 200 acres-escheated and granted to William Welling 1 September 1663
- 1653 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  George Clarke 100 acres
- 11 March 1653 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Anthony Hoskins 400 acres
- 20 January 1663 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  William Welling 200 acres
- 20 October 1665 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Major William Andrews 500 acres
- 26 May 1675 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Lt. Col. William Waters 700 acres
- (Box 12, Folder 11 (Begin Misc. reel #681))
  wills of the Tazewell and related families-copies
- (Box 12, Folder 11)
  ca. 1825-Sarah Nivison-Norfolk-incomplete
- (Box 12, Folder 11)
  n.d.-miscellaneous genealogical notes
- 1656 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Anne Littleton-recorded 16 November 1656-Northampton County
- 16 September 1679 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Southey Littleton-of Virginia-probably Accomack County and Northampton County-recorded at Albany NY
- 11 September 1732 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Gertrude Harmanson-Northampton County
- 4 January 1732/3 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  4 January 1732/3-William Aylett-recorded 17 March 1733-King William County
- 29 October 1751 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  William Tazewell-Northampton County
- 29 April 1768 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  John Nivison-Brunswick County
- 20 March 1795 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  John Stratton-Northampton County-noted recorded, no date
- 3 November 1796 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  William Langhorne-recorded 12 October 1797-Warwick County
- 7 May 1797 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Henry Tazewell-recorded 8 April 1799-James City County
- 29 April 1820 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  John Nivison-Norfolk County-note saying written by him 24 May 1820-this last date contradicts information saying died 13 May 1820 and is probably wrong-perhaps a recorded date
- 28 November 1820 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  William T. Nivison-Norfolk-memorandum of debts-memorandum made 7 October 1821 in Petersburg-codicil 15 October 1821
- 19 February 1825 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Sarah Nivison-Norfolk-note recorded 24 May 1830
- 16 May 1851 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  John N. Tazewell-Norfolk-notes repeat 3 July 1852-codicil 25 July 1853
- 17 September 1858 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  John N. Tazewell-Norfolk
- 2 December 1858 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell-recorded 28 May 1860-Norfolk
- 25 February 1868 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  John N. Tazewell-Norfolk-recorded 28 January 1869
- 25 February 1868 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- 22 May 1873 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Louisa N. Tazewell-recorded 5 November 1873-Norfolk
- 22 May 1873 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- 4 June 1888 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Edmund Bradford--Norfolk
- 19 March 1890 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Sally Tazewell-Norfolk
- (Box 12, Folder 12)
  wills-mainly copies
- 1656 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Ann Littleton-Northampton County-recorded November 1656
- 24 July 1673 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  William Andrews of Northampton County-recorded 28 August 1673
- 16 September 1679 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Southey Littleton possibly of Northampton or Accomack County-will recorded in New York
- 8 October 1685 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  William Waters-Northampton County-codicil 27 August 1688
- 19 August 1695 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Newton-Westmoreland County-codicil 21 December 1696-recorded 28 July 1697
- 9 April 1698 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Stringer-Northampton County-recorded 28 July 1698
- 18 March 1721/2 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  18 March 1721/2-Hillary Stringer-Northampton County-10 July 1722
- 11 September 1732 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- 29 October 1751 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  William Tazewell-Northampton County-recorded 19 September 1752
- 29 October 1751 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- 24 January 1752 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Samuel Skinker-King George County-recorded 6 February 1752
- 27 October 1753 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Sophia Tazewell-Northampton County-recorded 8 January 1754
- 24 May 1756 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Daniel Hutchings-Norfolk-codicil March 1766-proved in Southampton County Court 12 July 1792 and recorded
- 12 January 1761 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  George Camp-James City County-recorded 13 July 1761
- 29 April 1768 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Nivison-Brunswick County-proved 27 November 1769
- 3 January 1774 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  James Hunter-Princess Anne County-recorded 13 January 1774
- 10 January 1776 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  William Hunter-Princess Anne County
- 16 January 1776 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  George Veale of Portsmouth
- 22 February 1779 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Jonas Herbert-Norfolk County-copied August 1782
- 29 February 1784 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Peyton Randolph-Henrico County-recorded 7 July 1784
- 29 February 1784 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- 28 February 1786 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Willoughby-Norfolk County-recorded-19 September 1791
- 17 March 1787 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  William Wilson-Norfolk County-recorded-20 April 1787
- 13 February 1788 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Abraham Wormington-Norfolk-recorded-16 January 1789
- 11 June 1788 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Richard Bunting-Norfolk County-recorded 16 October 1788
- 24 August 1788 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Richard Taliaferro-James City County-recorded 14 December 1789
- 10 March 1790 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Henry Tazewell-James City County
- 1792 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Hunter's will [no first name-rough copy]
- 12 January 1792 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Archibald Campbell of Bermuda-proved 25 February 1792
- 21 April 1792 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John McLean of Shelburne County, Nova Scotia-copied 20 March 1793
- 20 March 1795 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Stratton-Northampton County-recorded 14 April 1795
- 20 March 1795 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Stratton of Northampton County
- 1 August 1795 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Peter Brunet of Norfolk-codicil 22 May 1797-codicil 9 June 1797, written at Providence RI
- April 1796 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  John Paradise-Middlesex County England, proved 30 August 1796
- 4 March 1797 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  will of Josiah Cowper-no location, perhaps Norfolk
- 9 June 1821 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  William Langborne-King William County-recorded 23 June 1823
- 7 October 1821 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  memorandum of William Nivison of Norfolk but in Petersburg regarding his will-an addendum dated 15 October
- (Box 12, Folder 13)
  n.d.-list of fines for Henry and John N. Tazewell-Henry for neglect of public worship and John for 22 absences from prayers and 11 tardy
- 8 November 1822 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-John's health-college and exams-church
- 13 November 1822 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to Henry and John N. Tazewell-opening an account at the bookstore-Henry wanting to leave Cambridge (Harvard)-need to be a productive member of society in some way
- 2 January 1823 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-John and Henry's dispute with H. W.[ickham?]-not a deliberate insult-hopes that they will accept W.'s apology-Tazewell and Wickham good friends-hoped the same for their sons-Edward Barry at school-pleased to hear of his prospects
- 9 March 1823 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-glad to hear that John is out and about-unhappy with Higginson's account-sending John a check-tells him to pay Higginson for Henry's account and his own-put rest in bank
- 11 April 1823 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-o.k. to put money in Higginson's hands but get full receipt-not happy with Higginson's accounts
- 24 May 1823 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-John's account and bills with Higginson-Henry's debt for a gun-pay for the gun and get the gun-plans for John's housing next year-Tazewell's health
- 3 July 1823 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-John's account-Henry's account
- 25 July 1823 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Littleton Waller Tazewell to John N. Tazewell-tells him to pay his debts